{"tossups": [{"question": "This man idolizes the \"intellectual and virginal manliness\" exempli\u2884ed by St. Sebastian and lives by the motto \"Durchhalten,\" or \"persevere,\" which he borrowed from Frederick the Great. A barber tells this man that \"we are all as old as we feel, but no older,\" in an effort to sell him hair dye. A boatman who ferries this man but refuses to tell him the cost, instead only ominously saying \"you will pay,\" is one of several redheaded men who menace him. He has a dream about the \"stranger god\" a\u29d4er becoming obsessed with a guest at the hotel in which he is staying. A\u29d4er seeing Jasiu (YAH-shoo) win a \u2884ght on the beach, this man dies of cholera contracted from overripe strawberries. For 10 points, what character lusts a\u29d4er the Polish boy Tadzio before perishing in Thomas Mann's novella Death in Venice?", "answer": "Gustav von Aschenbach [accept either underlined portion]", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Gustav von Aschenbach</u></b> [accept <b><u>either underlined portion</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Gustav von Aschenbach", "either underlined portion"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The first drafts of this piece were set to sections from Psalm 9 chosen with the help of Ivan Sollertinsky. This piece unusually features two harps, which first play in its second movement, originally titled \"Memories.\" The coda of this piece's allegro non troppo final movement quotes the opening theme of Anton Bruckner's Eighth Symphony. A section of this piece contains a pastiche combining a theme from the composer's earlier Nikolai Leskov\u2013inspired opera with the song \"You'll Find Me at Maxim's\" from Franz Lehha\u0301r's The Merry Widow; that section of this piece is a 22-bar march that repeats twelve times, with each instance adding more instruments and volume. For 10 points, what Dmitri Shostakovich symphony contains a theme representing the invasion of the title Soviet city?", "answer": "Leningrad Symphony [or Dmitri Shostakovich's Seventh Symphony; or Symphony no. 7 in C Major by Dmitri Shostakovich; accept Seventh Symphony or Symphony no. 7 after \"Shostakovich symphony\"]", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Leningrad Symphony</u></b> [or <b><u>Dmitri Shostakovich's Seventh Symphony</u></b>; or <b><u>Symphony no. 7 in C Major by Dmitri Shostakovich</u></b>; accept <b><u>Seventh Symphony</u></b>accept <b><u>Symphony no. 7</u></b> after \"Shostakovich symphony]", "acceptable": ["Leningrad Symphony", "Dmitri Shostakovich's Seventh Symphony", "Symphony no. 7 in C Major by Dmitri Shostakovich", "Seventh Symphony", "Symphony no. 7"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one of this author's poems, the speaker compares a \"catafalqued (KAT-ah-falk'd) king\" and a \"solitary man of war / among these frail vegetables\" to the title \"torpedo from the ocean\" that is \"navigating now / the waters of death.\" Another of his poems concludes about the title objects that \"beauty is twice / beauty / and what is good is doubly / good.\" This author of poems dedicated to a tuna and his own socks wrote another poem calling a lover a \"cemetery of kisses\" and a \"pit of debris\" who is \"standing like a sailor at the prow of a vessel.\" At the end of that poem by this author, the speaker proclaims \"it is the hour of departure\" after lamenting \"in you everything sank!\" For 10 points, what poet wrote the collections Elemental Odes and Twenty Love Poems and a Song of Despair?", "answer": "Pablo Neruda [or Ricardo Elie\u0301cer Neftali\u0301 Reyes Basoalto]", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Pablo <b><u>Neruda</u></b> [or <b><u>Ricardo Elie\u0301cer Neftali\u0301 Reyes Basoalto</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Pablo Neruda", "Ricardo Elie\u0301cer Neftali\u0301 Reyes Basoalto"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This condition occurs with a coagulation de\u2884ciency in Hermansky\u00c2\u2013Pudlak syndrome. Mutations in the P protein lead to this condition, which is why it is o\u29d4en a symptom of Prader\u00c2\u2013Willi (PRAH-dur vill-ee) syndrome. The copper-dependent enzyme absent in this condition hydroxylates and then oxidizes tyrosine to give a quinone. People with this condition have no RPE layer in their retinas. The opposite phenotype to this condition occurs in patients with Addison's or Cushing's disease because they overexpress melanocyte-stimulating hormones. The oculo\u00c2\u00b7taneous (ock-yoo-lo-TAY-nee-us) form of this condition o\u29d4en leads to deafness, vision trouble, and susceptibility to skin cancer. For 10 points, name this recessive condition in which the body can't produce melanin, which causes unpigmented skin.", "answer": "albinism [or word forms such as albino; or hypopigmentation; accept oculotaneous albinism; prompt on descriptive answers]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>albinism</u></b> [or <b><u>word forms such as albino</u></b>; or <b><u>hypopigmentation</u></b>; accept <b><u>oculotaneous albinism</u></b>; prompt on <u>descriptive answers</u>]", "acceptable": ["albinism", "word forms such as albino", "hypopigmentation", "oculotaneous albinism"], "promptable": ["descriptive answers"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A 1989 speech compares this man's story to that of Vietnamese refugees who greeted an American sailor with the cry \"hello, freedom man.\" One of his speeches describes four different kinds of love before concluding that an ideal community is \"knit together by the bonds of love.\" This man's notebooks, which were discovered and published by Noah Webster, detail his ideological split with John Wheelwright over the concept of \"Free Grace.\" During the Antinomian Controversy, this man presided over the blasphemy trial of Anne Hutchinson. While traveling aboard the ship Arabella, he gave a sermon claiming \"the eyes of all people are upon us.\" For 10 points, name this governor of Massachusetts Bay Colony whose sermon \"A Model of Christian Charity\" coined the phrase \"city upon a hill.\"", "answer": "John Winthrop", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>John Winthrop</u></b>", "acceptable": ["John Winthrop"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A player of this instrument wrote the songs \"Peace\" and \"Sister Sadie\" for the album Blowin' the Blues Away and another song whose bossa nova\u00c2\u2013inspired ostinato is quoted in Steely Dan's \"Rikki Don't Lose That Number.\" A player of this instrument released the best-selling solo jazz album in history, a recording of an hour-long improvised performance in the Cologne opera house. This was the instrument played by the composer of \"Song for My Father,\" Horace Silver. A player of this instrument released \"Ruby My Dear\" and \"Epistrophy\" on one of his many EPs titled Genius of Modern Music. That player of this instrument composed \"Straight, No Chaser\" and \"'Round Midnight.\" For 10 points, name this primary instrument of Keith Jarrett, Thelonious Monk, and Duke Ellington.", "answer": "piano [or pianoforte]", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>piano</u></b> [or <b><u>pianoforte</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["piano", "pianoforte"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "With Michael Maccoby, this thinker studied the social character of peons, free campesinos, and entrepreneurs in a Mexican village. E. O. Wilson adopted this thinker's term \"biophilia,\" which this thinker claimed was one of three orientations that produce all human forces in his book On Being Human. He argued that Marx's thought was centered on humanist existentialism in Marx's Concept of Man. Another book by this thinker lists authoritarianism, destructiveness, and conformity as mechanisms of performing the title action. He distinguished self-love from egocentrism or arrogance in a book arguing that the activity of love is a skill that can be developed. For 10 points name this member of the Frankfurt School who wrote The Art of Loving and Escape from Freedom.", "answer": "Erich Fromm [or Erich Seligmann Fromm]", "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Erich Fromm</u></b> [or <b><u>Erich Seligmann Fromm</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Erich Fromm", "Erich Seligmann Fromm"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Asymmetric induction occurs with Felkin\u00c2\u2013Anh selectivity or by a mechanism named for this process. This process can explain why, all else equal, the stability constant beta-1,1 (\"beta one one\") is usually greater than beta-1,2 (\"beta one two\"). The effect named for this process explains why siderophores (sih-DER-oh-fores) have such low K-sub-m values. The chirality of propeller compounds formed by this process is labeled lambda or delta. Complexometric titrations rely on titrants that can effect this process, which, unusually, is controlled by entropy. Ethylene\u00c2\u00b7di\u00c2\u00b7amine, or \"en,\" and its tetra-acetic (\"tetra\"-ah-SEE-tik) acid derivative E\u00c2\u00b7D\u00c2\u00b7T\u00c2\u00b7A facilitate this process because they're polydentate. For 10 points, what process, in which metals are surrounded by a clawlike ligand, is o\u29d4en used to treat heavy metal poisoning?", "answer": "chelation [or chelation control; or the chelate effect; prompt on \"binding\" to metals or similar answers; prompt on \"coordination\"]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>chelation</u></b> [or <b><u>chelation control</u></b>; or the <b><u>chelate effect</u></b>; prompt on <u>binding\" to metals</u> or <u>similar answers</u>; prompt on <u>coordination</u>]", "acceptable": ["chelation", "chelation control", "chelate effect"], "promptable": ["binding\" to metals", "similar answers", "coordination"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The leader of this political party released staged photos with kittens on the pseudo-lifestyle blog \"Notes of Hope.\" A\u29d4er a failed 2015 attempt by this party to oust one of its members via a national mail vote, its executive committee met in secret to oust that man anyway. This party changed its symbol to a blue rose as part of its \"de-demonization\" strategy. The leader of this party vowed to \"ruin the government's life\" while mobilizing opposition against a refugee camp nicknamed \"the Jungle.\" In 2015, this party expelled its founder a\u29d4er he referred to the Holocaust as a \"historical detail.\" In advance of an April 2017 presidential election, the leader of this party is polling ahead of rivals Benoit Hamon and Franc\u0327ois Fillon (ben-WAH hah-\"MOAN\" and frahn-SWAH fi-YOHN). For 10 points, what right-wing French party is led by Marine Le Pen?", "answer": "National Front [or Front National; or FN]", "category": "Current Events", "subcategory": "Current Events", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>National Front</u></b> [or <b><u>Front National</u></b>; or <b><u>FN</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["National Front", "Front National", "FN"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this story, a man who states that \"love is a dunghill . . . and I'm the cock that gets on it to crow\" reminisces about a woodcutter's house in the Gauertal (GAO-er-tahl), where a deserter with bloody feet was given socks so that he could hide from the police. A woman in this story repeatedly offers \"Tommy-ram broth\" to her husband, who calls her a \"rich bitch\" but resolves not to be cruel a\u29d4er he realizes he is dying. Its preface mentions a mysterious \"dried and frozen carcass of a leopard.\" In this story, a man suggests that death can \"have a wide snout like a hyena\" and imagines that Compton is \u29d4ying him up to the \"square top\" of the title location instead of taking him to Arusha. For 10 points, name this Ernest Hemingway story about the writer Harry, who dies of gangrene on the slopes of an African mountain.", "answer": "\"The Snows of Kilimanjaro\"", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>\"The Snows of Kilimanjaro\"</u></b>", "acceptable": ["\"The Snows of Kilimanjaro\""], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A revolutionary from this country was inspired to create its \u29d4ag a\u29d4er a late-night conversation about the philosophy of color with Johann Wolfgang von Goethe. A secret society called the Lautaro Lodge was founded by that man from this country, whose term as president of its \u2884rst republic was undermined by an 1812 earthquake. Jose\u0301 Antonio Pa\u0301ez defeated a Spanish army in this country at the Battle of Carabobo. A revolutionary from this country brie\u29d4y secured its independence a\u29d4er the Admirable Campaign and wrote a letter soliciting European support while exiled in Jamaica. Revolutionaries from this country include Francisco de Miranda and a man who served as dictator of Gran Colombia. Simo\u0301n Boli\u0301var was born in, for 10 points, what modern-day country's capital of Caracas?", "answer": "Venezuela [or Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela; or Repu\u0301blica Bolivariana de Venezuela]               ", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Venezuela</u></b> [or <b><u>Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela</u></b>; or <b><u>Repu\u0301blica Bolivariana de Venezuela</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Venezuela", "Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela", "Repu\u0301blica Bolivariana de Venezuela"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This book argues that, while the sciences of nature were born from the practices of investigation, the sciences of man arose from examination. This book claims that the change it traces was \"completed\" on January 22, 1840, with the opening of a place called Mettray. This book examines the history of mechanisms derived from leper colonies and the division of plague-ridden towns a\u29d4er its opening section, which describes how six horses failed to draw and quarter Robert-Franc\u0327ois Damiens (dahm-YEN). A structure discussed at length in this book \"assures the automatic functioning of power\" by imposing \"a state of conscious and permanent visibility.\" Jeremy Bentham's \"Panopticon\" symbolizes the modern society of surveillance in, for 10 points, what book about \"the birth of the prison\" by Michel Foucault?", "answer": "Discipline and Punish: The Birth of the Prison [or Surveiller et punir: Naissance de la prison]", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Discipline and Punish: The Birth of the Prison</u></b> [or <b><u>Surveiller et punir: Naissance de la prison</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Discipline and Punish: The Birth of the Prison", "Surveiller et punir: Naissance de la prison"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A frequency for these particles contains a factor of the cube root of \"six pi squared times number density.\" Their spectrum has dips due to the presence of a Fermi surface in the Kohn anomaly. Rudolf Peierls (\"PIE-earls\") demonstrated that momentum isn't conserved in a scattering process that involves three of these particles and is balanced by a nonzero k-space vector. Their interactions with electrons lead to the formation of Cooper pairs in BCS theory. On a plot of frequency versus wavevector, the dispersion curves that touch the origin correspond to \"acoustic\" particles of this type. Imposing a cutoff frequency for these particles leads to a temperature-cubed dependence for heat capacity at low temperatures in the Debye (deh-\"BYE\") model. For 10 points, what quasi-particles are the quanta of energy for lattice vibrations?", "answer": "phonons", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>phonons</u></b>", "acceptable": ["phonons"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a reimagining of this poem, the speaker warns that \"hunger shall make thy modest zone / and cheat fond death of all but bone\" and offers the addressee \"peace and plenty, bed and board, / that chance employment may afford.\" This poem's speaker states that \"we will sit upon the rocks\" and look upon \"shallow Rivers to whose falls melodious birds sing madrigals.\" In a reply to this poem, its addressee refuses offers of a \"belt of straw and ivy buds\" and \"coral clasps and amber studs.\" Cecil Day-Lewis's response to this poem incorporates its two closing lines, which mention \"these delights thy mind may move.\" Sir Walter Raleigh wrote a \"nymph's reply\" to, for 10 points, what pastoral poem by Christopher Marlowe in which the title character urges \"come live with me and be my love\"?", "answer": "\"The Passionate Shepherd to His Love\"", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>\"The Passionate Shepherd to His Love\"</u></b>", "acceptable": ["\"The Passionate Shepherd to His Love\""], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "According to Diego Dura\u0301n, the Aztecs beheaded and \u29d4ayed people of this type every September in honor of a goddess of corn named \"seven serpent,\" or Chicomecoatl (chee-koh-meh-koh-AH-tul). The question of whether Arianrhod (ar-YAHN-rohd) could replace Goewin (go-win) in a seat reserved for people of this type was answered when she stepped over a magic wand belonging to Math, who was required always to rest his feet on people of this type. A select group of people of this type could be buried alive at the Evil Field, or Campus Sceleratus (skeh-leh-RAH-tus). In medieval legend, only people of this type had the ability to tame unicorns. The epithet \"Parthenos\" denotes Athena as a goddess of this type. Women tasked with maintaining the hearth of Vesta were, for 10 points, what type of people who, like the hunt goddess Diana, were characterized by their chastity?", "answer": "virgins [accept maidens; accept young women before \"Arianrhod\"; prompt on \"women\"; prompt on \"young women\" a\u29d4er \"Arianrhod\"]", "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>virgins</u></b> [accept <b><u>maidens</u></b>; accept <b><u>young women</u></b> before \"Arianrhod; prompt on <u>women</u>; prompt on <u>young women\" a\u29d4er \"Arianrhod</u>]", "acceptable": ["virgins", "maidens", "young women"], "promptable": ["women", "young women\" a\u29d4er \"Arianrhod"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This king forged a papal order in order to kidnap a reformed courtesan named La Brognina (la brohn-YEE-na) from a convent. A bread-and-egg soup was supposedly invented to feed this king a\u29d4er he was defeated in battle. On his orders, troops carried out the executions of religious dissenters in the Massacre of Me\u0301rindol (MAY-reen-dohl). Jean de La Fore\u0302t (\"de la\" for-AY) negotiated an alliance between Suleiman the Magni\u2884cent and this king, who woke to \u2884nd an anti-Catholic poster on his bedroom door, sparking the Affair of the Placards. He wrote to his mother, Louise of Savoy, that \"all is lost to me save honor and life\" a\u29d4er he was captured at the Battle of Pavia. This king held a summit with a northern rival at the Field of the Cloth of Gold. For 10 points, name this Valois king of France, a contemporary of Charles V and Henry VIII.", "answer": "Francis I of France [or Franc\u0327ois I of France; prompt on \"Francis\" or \"Franc\u0327ois\"]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Francis I of France</u></b> [or <b><u>Franc\u0327ois I of France</u></b>; prompt on <u>Francis</u> or <u>Franc\u0327ois</u>]", "acceptable": ["Francis I of France", "Franc\u0327ois I of France"], "promptable": ["Francis", "Franc\u0327ois"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This book advises the reader not to be surprised by oppression of the poor because \"one of\u2884cial watches over another of\u2884cial, and there are higher of\u2884cials over them.\" This book echoes Isaiah with its line \"for who can make that straight, which he hath made crooked.\" In Hebrew, the \u2884rst word of this text is \"hevel,\" and it concludes with the admonition to \"fear God\" and \"keep his commandments.\" This book observes that \"the heart of the wise is in the house of mourning; but the heart of fools is in the house of mirth.\" This book opens with a preacher identi\u2884ed as \"the Son of David, King in Jerusalem,\" who is later addressed as Koheleth, proclaiming \"vanity of vanities, all is vanity.\" For 10 points, name this contemplative book of the Old Testament that is attributed to Solomon.", "answer": "Ecclesiastes [accept Koheleth or Kohelet before \"Koheleth\"]", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Ecclesiastes</u></b> [accept <b><u>Koheleth</u></b>accept <b><u>Kohelet</u></b> before \"Koheleth]", "acceptable": ["Ecclesiastes", "Koheleth", "Kohelet"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "For u and v in a real vector space, a combination denoted by this term is the set \"one minus lambda\" times u plus \"lambda times v,\" where lambda is between zero and one, and is a special case of an af\u2884ne combination. Functions with this property have a positive semi-de\u2884nite Hessian. If a function has this property on an interval, Jensen's inequality requires the function's value at the midpoint of the interval to be less than or equal to the average of the function's values at the endpoints. The set of all combinations denoted by this term forms a \"hull\" also denoted by it. It's possessed by a function if the second derivative is not negative on the interval \"a comma b,\" or if a line segment connecting a and b lies above the function's graph. For 10 points, what property of a function is equivalent to being concave upward?", "answer": "convex [or obvious equivalents, such as convexity; accept concave upward before \"concave\"; do not accept or prompt on \"concave\" or \"concavity\" or \"concave down(ward)\"]", "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>convex</u></b> [or <b><u>obvious equivalents, such as convexity</u></b>; accept <b><u>concave upward</u></b> before \"concave; do not accept or prompt on \"concave\" or \"concavity\" or \"concave down\"]", "acceptable": ["convex", "obvious equivalents, such as convexity", "concave upward"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": ["concave", "concavity", "concave down"], "metadata": "ward"}, {"question": "This man's chief patron, Amadeo dal Pozzo, commissioned a two-part series on the Book of Exodus that includes The Adoration of the Golden Calf. The \u2884nal chapter of Erwin Panofsky's Meaning in the Visual Arts discusses the ambiguity of a scene painted by this man that was earlier depicted by Guercino. The landscape surrounding Philip Johnson's Glass House was inspired by this man's The Funeral of Phocion (FOH-kee-on), an original of which hangs in the building itself. At the top of one of this man's paintings, Aurora guides Apollo's chariot on a dark cloud across the sky. Poverty, Labor, Wealth, and Pleasure stand in a circle with locked hands in this man's A Dance to the Music of Time. For 10 points, what French Baroque artist depicted shepherds examining a tomb in his Et in Arcadia ego?", "answer": "Nicolas Poussin (poo-SAHN)", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Nicolas Poussin</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Nicolas Poussin"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "poo-SAHN"}, {"question": "A character nicknamed a\u29d4er this animal narrates his rise from poverty in a Booker-winning novel framed as a letter to Chinese premier Wen Jiabao. One of these animals, which travels with a smaller companion to an island made of algae and populated by meerkats, takes its name from two separate victims of shipboard cannibalism. Aravind Adiga created a character named Balram in a novel titled for a \"white\" one of these animals. One of these animals in\u2884ltrates Akela's wolf pack as part of an attempt to hunt Mowgli. One of these animals named Richard Parker spends 227 days on a lifeboat with the title character of Yann Martel's The Life of Pi. The villain of The Jungle Book, Shere Khan, is, for 10 points, what type of big cat that, proverbially, cannot change its stripes?", "answer": "tigers [or Panthera tigris; or P. tigris; accept The White Tiger; prompt on \"big cats\"]", "subcategory": "Other Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>tigers</u></b> [or <b><u>Panthera tigris</u></b>; or <b><u>P. tigris</u></b>; accept <b><u>The White Tiger</u></b>; prompt on <u>big cats</u>]", "acceptable": ["tigers", "Panthera tigris", "P. tigris", "The White Tiger"], "promptable": ["big cats"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The day before this battle, the winning commander received Franc\u0327ois Ge\u0301rard's (zheh-RAHRD's) portrait of his young son, which that commander set up outside his tent for his generals to admire. Auguste de Caulaincourt (koh-lahn-KOOR) died in a cavalry charge that captured this battle's central defensive structure, the Raevsky (\"rye\"-EV-ski) Redoubt. This battle marks the \u2884nal narrowing prior to the color change in an infographic created by Charles Joseph Minard. Arrowhead-shaped earthworks called \u29d4e\u0300ches (\"flesh\") were created for this battle by Pyotr Bagration, who was mortally wounded during it. One commander's refusal to commit his Imperial Guard may have been a critical mistake in this battle, which was a pyrrhic victory over Mikhail Kutuzov. For 10 points, name this 1812 battle that marked the climax of Napoleon's invasion of Russia.", "answer": "Battle of Borodino", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Battle of Borodino</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Battle of Borodino"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}